Guide to the Jacques Barzun's Collection of Hector Berlioz Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IX: Audiovisual Materials
  - Subseries IX.1: Audiotapes
    - Colin Davis, Jacques Barzun, Eric Salzman: Hector Berlioz and Friends, Parts 1 & 2, Jun. 1970, (2 reels 1/4 inch magnetic tape, 50 min. ) (Box 44)
    - unidentified, (2 reels 1/4 inch magnetic tape, ) (Box 44)
  - Subseries IX.2: Still Images and Memorabilia
    Subseries contains photographs, original art, postcards, illustrations for Barzun's works on Berlioz, and ephemera relating to Berlioz and Barzun
    - Caricature of Hector Berlioz by Carjat, (Oversize flat, ) (Box 45)
    - Caricature of Berlioz from Satyrisches Bild, (Oversize flat, ) (Box 45)
    - Mounted print of Berlioz photograph, (b&w, Oversize flat) (Box 45)
    - A large bound copy of Berlioz' Manuscripts: 1837 - 1858; ( photostat), (Oversize flat, ) (Box 45)
    - Booklet from a Philips record set of Les Troyens, (Oversize flat, ) (Box 45)
    - Mounted prints of Berlioz and Smithson photographs, bust of Berlioz, related images [Illustrations for Berlioz and Romantic Century], (10 Oversize flat, b&w) (Box 46)
    - Images from Charivari and Le Foyer, (5 Oversize flat, b&w) (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Berlioz Image and Medal, Oct. 1909 (Box 46)
    - Louis Armstrong playing trumpet, Berlioz head on background, (Oversize flat, b&w photo phrint, ) (Box 46)
      [From the files of Life]
    - Fondation Hector Berlioz plaque (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Pictures and photographs of Berlioz, Smithson and family (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Postcards related to Berlioz (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Berlioz manuscripts photos, (67 b&w 35 mm slides, ) (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Photos of illustrations for Berlioz and Romantic Century, (26 b&w negatives, ) (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Portraits of other artists (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Harriet Smithson (Berlioz first wife) theater programs, 1829 - 1830 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Photos of Berlioz Sculptures, (6 b&w print, ) (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Maison de Berlioz photos, (8 b&w print, ) (Box 47, Folder 9)
      [Faded]
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, (13 b&w print, ) (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Pictures (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook of preformances of Benvenuto Cellini and The Trojans, London, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 12)
- Series X: Microfilms
  - Manuscript and corrections of Berlioz Benvenuto Cellini, (1 reel ) (Box 21)
  - New Letters of Berlioz, 1860-1868, Second Edition, (1 reel ) (Box 21)
    [# 77-2334]
  - Berlioz and the Romantic Century, Vols. I, II, Third Edition., (1 reel ) (Box 49)
  - Berlioz, Hector - Manuscripts, British Museum, (1 reel ) (Box 49)
  - Berlioz, Hector - Manuscripts, (1 reel ) (Box 49)
    [Proof copy, corrections on margins]
  - Berlioz - selected pages from: Le Corsaire (Aug. 1823-Jan. 1824); Le Monde Dramatique (1835), Le Renovateur (1833)., (1 reel ) (Box 49)
  - Berlioz letters: to Johan Von Herbeck (Mar. 15, 1867), to Mme Estelle Fornier ([1867]), to Bertold Damcke (Jul. 29, 1856), to Pauline Viardot (Nov. 19, 1853), to Pres. De la Section de Musique., (1 reel ) (Box 49)
  - Berlioz, Hector - Manuscripts: Grenoble letters, La Sombra de la Noche, La Confession de la Nina, (1 reel ) (Box 49)
  - Berlioz, Hector: Evenings With the Orchestra, (1 reel ) (Box 49)
  - Berlioz and His Century (One vol., paper edit.)`, (1 reel ) (Box 49)
  - Jacques Barzun: Ego I and Ego II (? Diary), (1 reel ) (Box 49)
  - Berlioz: Les Troyens score., (1 reel ) (Box 49)
  - Oversized cataloged manuscripts - see Manuscript series. (Box 48, Folder 1 - 4)